“著名的科W家和慈善家也乳酪大王和三孩子的父H：
s翰?海?福里斯特意外死亡”
It was a quiet day at the Rigby
Reardon Detective Agency.
e格比?里D商绞账平o的一天
I had a hangover, and business was so
slow I was rereading old newspapers.
我宿醉醒，]有生意上T，eo事看f蠹。
I was even thinking of closing
up the office for a few days...
我甚至在想把商绞账PT滋
when all of a sudden...
就在@r，美女炮友自由祥T了。。
- Mr Reardon?
- That's right.
e格比先生幔
正式在下！
My...
我...
My name... my...
我芳名...我...
In all my years in the business,
I'd never seen anything like her.
行走江湖@N多年，奈匆^@等尤物！
“天⒔荡笕戊端谷艘玻必⑾硪豢凇
“一吻定音”plus
Was she real? There was
only one way to find out.
尼@不是在做舭桑浚恐挥幸方法能z一下。
But I remembered Marlowe's words.
但是@有`R涞拿言
don`t fall in love with a client
“不要和客舫膳谟眩即便“一η椤币膊恍校
What the hell does Marlowe know?
R涠毛，他哪^@等尤物
She was real all right.
她L得太尼正c了，心中陡然o惦b小鹿。
What are you doing?
你在摸我中咪咪致铮
Adjusting your breasts.
只是你的乳房放M你的胸罩e而已（星硪玻。
You fainted and they...
shifted all outta whack.
你才倒了，乳房男卣盅e跑了出
- There.
- Thank you.
F在w位了
xx。
You're welcome.
不用x我的手。
Thank you. I... I apologise
for my dramatic entrance.
xx，我很抱歉，才MT那⌒缘囊荒
It's just when I saw the...
newspaper headlines...
正好看蠹的大祟}
（w育版）道奇又了.
- You must be quite a Dodgers fan.
- No, I saw... the front page.
你肯定是道奇的X女粉z。
不，我看...^版
“s翰?海?福里斯特意外死亡”
- What's your name, Dollface?
- Juliet Forrest.
“中乳童”，芳名？
茱~?福里斯特
Forrest...
福里斯特....
Daughter of the big cheesemaker. You
could use a cup of my famous java.
乳酪大王的千金，你可以硪槐我很M意爪哇咖啡。
Cheese was Daddy's hobby.
He was a scientist.
乳酪是爸爸的酆谩
他是一名科W家。
- Quite an accident he had.
- That's what I came to see you about.
超速{意外事故而死，
@就是我磉@e找你的原因。
You don't think it was an accident.
You think he was murdered.
你J椴皇且馔馐鹿剩
你J槭侵\？
How did you know?
你咋知道？
It's my business to know,
Miss Forrest. Sit down.
我靠@吃，
美女先坐下
What makes you think
it wasn't an accident?
你有啥C幔
Just before it... it happened...
就在家父意外死亡之前...
he behaved very erratically, writing
out lists of names, dozens of them.
他行楫常，了名危e面有凳人
He wrote them on blotters and
scratch pads, whatever was handy.
他把它在板和便{，不像手的
Here's one of the lists...
or part of one.
@是便{一部分
It's from a dollar bill.
碜杂谝幻涝的n票
Somehow I got the feeling he was
the victim of a giant conspiracy.
不知何故，我感X他是一巨大\的受害者。
You deducted murder and a
giant conspiracy from this?
你自己X海中演[的巨大\碜造哆@？
You think I'm too impulsive,
don't you, Mr Reardon?
你J槭窃谑芨星轵使幔
不是幔坷登先生
Maybe.
可能是
Maybe not.
可能不是
If you want me to investigate your
father's death, I get $10 a day.
如果要我{查你父H的死因，10美刀一天
Plus expenses.
加上_N
Will $200 be enough in
advance, Mr Reardon?
A支200刀蛄税桑
- For $200 I'd shoot my grandmother.
- That won't be necessary.
200刀我可以去⑽业淖婺福@玩笑有c^了
You never can tell. On my last case, I
had to throw my brother out of a plane.
你永h不知道。在我的最後一案子中，我不得不把我弟弟扔下wC
Where'd your father keep
his correspondence?
你父H一般在哪e看信件什N的？
He had a small private office
downtown. Here's the key.
他在市中心有一小私人k公室。@是匙
Thank you, Mr Reardon.
I appreciate this.
感x你接手@案子，真心感x
- Miss Forrest?
- Yes?
福里斯特小姐。在
Save me some shoe leather if you
told me what address this key fits.
如果你告V我地址，我就能少跑些路
It was 429 Firehouse Row.
429 消防站 _
Pretty seedy part of town
for a renowned scientist.
於一著名的科W家碚f@小蚱婆f的
It was the only place he could
experiment with cheese...
@是家父乳酪的唯一地方
without the smell
bothering the neighbours.
不有馕厄}_居
I'll see what I can turn up.
我看我大有作橐环的
Good day, Mr Reardon.
祝好
On my way to Firehouse Row, I tried
not to think of Juliet Forrest.
在去死者k公室的路上，我量不去想那“中乳童”美女
I hadn't seen a body like that...
但是“中乳童”那曼妙的身姿，我震精......
since I'd solved the case of the
murdered girl with the big tits.
自纳洗未笊饺赴钢校救^那差c被\⑴孩後
I had no trouble finding
Dr Forrest's cheese lab.
我毫不M力地找到了“中乳童”他爹的乳酪室
It smelled like the
number on the door.
它起硐耖T上的a
Inside, I turned up
something interesting.
M到e面，我lF了些有意思的|西。
"To John Forrest, a dear man who, like
his cheeses, gets stronger with age."
致H鄣募s翰?福里斯特，祝你像乳酪一樱老而“挺”
"Love, Kitty."
廴P蒂
So the old renowned scientist
was getting a little on the side.
原磉@是著名老科W家的“嫩草枕L”
"Enemies of Carlotta."
卡洛塔的橙
"Friends of Carlotta."
卡洛塔的盟友
"Kitty Collins"?
P蒂?柯林斯
Sounds like company.
有人向@e走^砹
Exterminator.
害x除┩其N
Just a minute.
等一下
Come in.
M
Sit down.
坐吧
There's some cookies on the table.
那e有乾。
Have one.
睃c
（此人榘?拉德--Alan Ladd，@蚨碜 "This Gun For Hire")
（注：碜浴r光W”，@些演T注解找到真尼不容易，r光W是挺I的）
Good, aren't they?
味道不e
Guess to be a really good exterminator
you have to enjoy killing things.
猜你是不e的害x除┩其NT，你必享受“搞死小全家老小”
（@幼鳎我o12分）
- Yes?
- I'd like to see Miss Forrest.
神R事？
我是碚腋＠锼固匦〗愕
- Who shall I say is calling?
- Mr Reardon. Tell her I've been shot.
你是哪？
老子是大名鼎鼎的躺真探――里登，告V她我中了
Very good, sir.
好的
- May I tell her by whom?
- No. I don't know myself.
我可以告V她是l_的幔坎唬我都不知道是l_的
Are you all right? You look as
though you're going to faint.
你好幔磕憧雌砗孟褚倒了
Faint? Ha!
昏倒？
Never.
聿
- Catch me.
- Sorry.
抓住我，Σ黄
I'm a butler... not a catcher.
我是男管家，不是接球手
―l功洹
Dollface...
中乳童...
我靠.y道是髡f中的：“吸星大法，第七重？？”那什N碇？？？
What are you doing?!
我想！我想！我使畔耄
Γ　翱诘降怼保浚
It should feel better now.
感X好c了吧？
- Where'd you learn that?
- At camp.
你在哪W的？？任我行教你的？？
我是在n外活W的？
- You learned that at girls' camp?
- It's really for snakebite, but...
你是在那NｉT女孩的IW的？那e真有被毒舌咬^的，
I find it works for everything.
但是我後碇道@“口活”用途V泛。
You mumbled about Kitty Collins and
Swede Anderson being on a list.
你含糊地自言自ZP蒂?柯林斯和瑞典人安德森在名紊
- "Friends of Carlotta"?
- That's right. Do you know them?
卡洛塔的盟友
α耍你JR他幔
Kitty was...
P蒂是......
Kitty was someone Daddy trifled
with after Mother dried up.
P蒂是我爸的一新g娘
And Swede was Kitty's boyfriend.
瑞典人安德森是她炮友
Where are they now?
他F在在哪
The last I heard, they
were in Santa Barbara.
我最後一次f他在}塔巴巴拉
He used to be a boxer. Now
he works in a gas station...
他曾是一拳羰帧，F在一加油站工作
And she sings in a private club.
P蒂在一私人俱凡砍歌
You may be interested in this.
I found it in Daddy's study.
你可能@感d趣，我在爸爸房找到的。
"Thanks for the check.
In case I'm indisposed..."
xx你的支票，如果我X得不舒服...
"...the dollar you gave me for safekeeping
is in the top of the sugar bowl."
你o我保管的美元放在糖碗的部
- "Shh."
- Why?
u，槊？
No. This.
不是@意思，上面的
No, no, no. That's not "Shh."
It's S-H-H. Samuel H Hastings.
不不，不是@意思，不是u，是S-H-H，撒母耳?H?赫斯廷斯。
My brother-in-law.
Or at least he was.
我妹夫或者至少他曾是
He and my sister Leona are
separated. He's a hopeless drunk.
他和我的妹妹李W娜分_了。他是醉如泥的人
- Where is he now?
- I don't know.
他F在在哪？
不知道
Get your sister Leona for me.
R上M你妹妹李W娜
All right.
好吧
I'm afraid she may not
be very much help.
我怕她不太意兔
- She's very disturbed.
- How disturbed?
她心智有些失常。
有多失常？
She's been diagnosed as a
paranoid hypochondriac.
她被\槠
- Doctors think she may be faking.
- I'll know after one word if she is.
t生J樗是b的。
她f之後，我就知道真瘟
（此人榘虐爬?斯坦威克--Barbara Stanwyck，@蚨碜 "Sorry - Wrong Number")
- Hello?
- She's faking.
哪位？
她是b的
Mrs Hastings? My name's Reardon.
Sorry to hear your father's passed on.
是赫斯廷斯夫人幔渴堑摹
我是里D，很不幸的告V你，你爹去西天了
No, he hasn't. He won't
be back till Sunday.
不，他]有，到星期日前他不回怼
Sunday? You don't
understand, Mrs Hastings.
星期日？你]有理解，赫斯廷斯夫人
I'm investigating
your father's death.
我正在{查你父H的死因
My father called me from Chicago
tonight. He never mentioned a word!
我父H今晚闹ゼ痈缃o我打。他]有提到
Maybe it slipped his mind.
也S是他忘了
Look, uh, your father
is dead, Mrs Hastings.
你看，你父H_浩了，@是事，赫斯廷斯夫人
Your sister Juliet feels his
death wasn't an accident.
你姐姐茱~J槟愀赣H不是死于意外
What are you talking about?
你在f啥子？
I had a long talk with him
just a little while ago.
我才和他了很久
- He told me terrible things about you.
- Listen, you phony fruitcake!
他告V我P於你的可怕的事情，著，你@假b的U物c心
Sorry I called you a fruitcake.
I just don't have time to listen to...
不好意思，我才叫你U物c心，我只是F在]rg@些]用的|西
All right, don't listen! Who cares?
好吧，那就不要，老子才吊你？
Your sister has a lot to
learn about phone courtesy.
你老妹阂稽cY都]有
You got any idea how
I could locate Sam?
你知道如何找到撒母耳幔
You might ask the bartenders
along 5th Street.
你就得沿著第五大街{酒了
I'll call you if
I turn up anything.
我打o你，如果有lF
Oh... If I'm not home, leave a message
with the butler or the cleaning woman.
哦，如果我出去了，o管家或者女蛄粞跃秃
Cleaning woman.
女
Cleaning woman! Cleaning woman!
女颍∨颍
Sorry.
不好意思
Why did you do that?
你才抽啥子“羊d”？
When I was seven years old...
在我7qr
my father ran off
with the cleaning...
我父H和一女蛩奖剂
My mother died of a broken heart.
我的心碎而死。
Now every time someone
says cleaning...
F在每到有人f女颍
- ...I go berserk.
- Oh! You poor dear.
我就獠淮蛞惶
哦！好可z
I don't blame you
for strangling me.
我不怪你才的l狂
I'll never say it again.
我不再f那~了
Thanks.
xx
So long, Dollface.
再，中乳童。
I legged it down 5th Street
looking for Samuel H Hastings.
我步行在第五街上，ふ胰瞿付?H?赫斯廷斯。
It was a street of frustrated
hopes and broken dreams.
@l街充M了沮屎推扑榈
Everything was cheap, cut-rate. Even
the prostitutes were having a sale.
一切都那N廉r，妓女也是80元一次“速食包]”那N。
There was no problem finding Hastings.
He owed money to every bartender.
在@e找到赫斯廷斯不是}，他欠了一屁股的酒X
He was staying at the Hotel Ward on 5th
Street. It used to be on 8th Street...
他F在寄居在第五街上一叫沃德的旅^e，^去是在第八街
But they took so many rubber checks,
it bounced all the way across town.
但是@PM城的_了太多空^支票，都被拒了
I went to his room and knocked.
我F在淼竭@P住，敲T先
（此人槔?米m德--Ray Milland，@蚨碜 "The Lost Weekend")
- Hastings? Sam Hastings?
- Who is it?
赫斯廷斯在幔咳瞿付?赫斯廷斯?
哪找?
My name is Reardon. I...
have a proposition for ya.
我是里D，我斫o你美差
But not today. Does
it have to be today?
但不是今天。
必是今天幔
- Yeah.
- Come on Monday.
Γ星期一
- I got that money for ya.
- What money?
我有Xo你。
什NX？
There's a dollar bill
hidden in your sugar bowl.
你的糖罐子e藏著一美元
I'll give you five bucks for it.
我人傻X多，用5美元Q
- You could buy a lotta booze with that.
- Just a minute.
你可以I不少酒了。
稍等
Look in the top.
看w子部
It fits perfectly. Most of
the names are illegible...
拼起硗昝溃但是好多名字o法辨J
But I can work out Kitty
Collins and Swede Anderson.
但是我能找到P蒂?柯林斯和瑞典人安德森
But what does "FOC" mean?
但是，“操?我”啥意思？
It's a slang word. When a man and a
woman are in love, the man puts his...
@是俚Z，一男人和女人有η槭蔷陀眠@......
No, no. Written here. F-O-C.
不ΣΓ@e的是F-O-C.
Oh. Unless I miss my guess, that
stands for "Friends of Carlotta".
哦，我猜一下，@是“卡洛塔的盟友”
- I'm impressed.
- You think that's impressive...
你玩我吧
@才是在逗你....
（yuan18--原字幕）
There I was, standing like a kid
doing corny tricks for her...
我F在玩老掉牙的把蚨核
Driving miles out of my
way just to see her.
_V看她，撞死路人
Why?
槊？
What are you thinking, Mr Reardon?
里D先生，你F在是在想“槲业娜榉恐匦w位帷保
So long, Dollface. I'll be in
Santa Barbara if you need me.
再，中乳童，如果你^m雇我，我就去}巴巴拉。
I found out Kitty Collins was
working at the Brentwood Room.
lFP蒂?柯林斯在布特伍德?姆工作
The Brentwood Room.
@e就是布特伍德?姆
Where rich women go to meet rich
men so they can have rich kids.
“操，P生P，耗子生捍虻囟础
Miss Collins?
柯林斯小姐幔
（此人榘娃?加德{--Ava Gardner，@蚨碜 "The Killers")
Kitty wouldn't give me any information
if she thought I was a private eye...
如果她J槲沂且私家商剑她不o我任何Y
Excuse me.
打_一下
So I decided to act like a
big-shot movie producer.
所以我成一大影u片人
- My name's Reardon. I make movies.
- How wonderful of you.
我的名字叫里D。我拍影的。
到你真好
- You like boxing pictures?
- I'm afraid I've never seen one.
你喜g拳D片。
我恐怕]^。
I'm casting a big boxing picture at RKO.
I'm looking for a singer. You interested?
在基斯-W菲厄姆oV播c影上，我在I湟拳舸颍我F在正在找一歌手，你有d趣幔
The idea of two men beating each
other to a pulp makes me ill.
大男人相互W，@N低趣味我感到不舒服。
Well, I'm also doing
a religious picture.
是吧，我一直是慎的做影的。
The Story of Saint... Betty.
@故事是有P於}…蒂
You know, the... nun who
taught the lepers how to sing.
她教麻L病人如何唱歌
- How wonderful of you.
- Thanks.
你是如此有z之心。
xx
John Hay Forrest said you
were a friend of Carlotta's.
s翰?海?福里斯特f你是卡洛塔的盟友
Will you excuse me?
不好意，x_一下
I must have hit a nerve.
She went white as a ghost.
我肯定是打中她的要害了，她像一白色幽`一娱W了
The next day I tailed Kitty
Collins to a fancy restaurant.
第二天，我尾SP蒂?柯林斯到了高餐d
Midway through the meal, she noticed
me and did a pretty strange thing.
在局中，我注意到了我，然後做了件十分奇怪的事
She took off her
brooch and ditched it.
她拿掉了她的胸，然後扔掉了
I had a pretty good idea where.
我R上就有了主x
Hold it, pal. I'm from
the health department.
等一下，服丈，我是l生局的巡zT
We have a report that your soup
has too much jewellery in it.
我接到螅你的e有^多珠
"EOC." Enemies of Carlotta.
卡洛塔的橙
The only name on the list that wasn't
crossed out was Swede Anderson.
只有一名字在名紊]有被掉，瑞典人安德森
I decided to drop in on him
before they crossed him out too.
我去一下他，在e人把值羲之前
Swede wasn't living in luxury.
瑞典人安德森在愕墓寓
As a matter of fact, for a moment,
I thought he wasn't living at all.
事上，我看到他的那一刻，我以樗死NN了
Swede?
瑞典人
Sorry, Swede. I thought
you'd been murdered.
Σ黄穑瑞典人，我以槟阋呀被\⒘
Come on, wake up!
不要b死，起
Come on, Swede.
不要b死，瑞典人
（此人椴特?m卡斯特--Burt Lancaster，@蚨碜 "The Killers")
You need a cup of my java.
你需要一杯我秘制的爪哇u咖啡
尼M入共a主x社了幔堪葱璺峙溧拢咖啡粉不要X？一下放@N多多？
大家不用急，coffe粉R上就放完：）
{尼？？要加u蛋？
尼是“咖啡荷包蛋”plus幔
果然是碜宰νu，野U人的喝法！
You're up. Good. The java
will be ready in a minute.
起砹司秃茫我秘制的爪哇u咖啡一就得。
This is never gonna heal.
@直是口上散“地嫌汀保不可能好得了啊！
尼.@就是髡f中的：“吸星大法，第八重？？”那什N碇？？？
What are you doing?!
我想！我想！我使畔耄
Γ　按骄d舌h”？？
Anyway, my guess is by now Kitty
Collins is a million miles from here.
我猜F在基蒂?柯林斯是x@阂话偃f英里的地方
Do you think Swede was killed by the
same man who murdered my father?
你J⑺廊鸬淙撕臀腋赣H是同一苋笋R？
Hold it, Dollface. No one's proved
your father's been murdered...
慢c，中乳童 ]有CC明你的猜y。
yet.
至少F在
But you may be right about
this being a conspiracy.
但是你的猜y@是\可能是Φ
It's big. Maybe too big
for me to handle alone.
@是大\，可能我一人理不了
Get me a cup of java, will ya?
o我肀爪哇咖啡
00:24:03,200-> 00:24:07,489
（此人楹喔トR?U嘉--Humphrey Bogart，@蚨碜 "The Big Sleep")
- Yeah?
- Hello, Marlowe?
砹
是R幔
- Oh, hello, Bernie.
- No, it's me, Rigby.
哦，伯尼
不是，我是e格比
What's up?
咋了
I'm on an important case. I need
your help. How soon can you get here?
我正在k@天地泣鬼神的大案，需要你碇我一臂之力，你最快啥r能?
- I haven't had breakfast.
- Breakfast? You're late for lunch, pal.
我]吃早。
尼，F在都吃午了
- It's two o'clock.
- Two o'clock?
下午牲c了。
下午牲c？
Hustle on over here. I'll make
you a cup of my famous java.
坐火箭磉@e，我o你泡一杯我最M意爪哇咖啡
- I'd rather buy my own.
- Suit yourself. See ya in a half-hour.
我I我自己的
S你便，半小r後
And Marlowe. Wear a
tie, for God's sake.
有R洌打上IВ看在上帝的份上
What's that?
那是啥？
I found it in Daddy's desk.
我在我爸的桌子上找到@。
It looks like a key to one of those
lockers at the train station.
像是火站ξ的匙
Number's been filed off. What's
it say on that envelope?
底直慌掉了，信封上的什N
"Most recent rat."
最近的老鼠
（美女，你的表情才像吃了只老鼠）
- Very clever.
- You understand what it means?
很清楚。
你知道意思了？
Just a hunch. You know the Chinese have
a different animal for every year?
直X而已，你知道中年份游锷肖幔
- Yes.
- Unless I miss my guess...
知道
除非我猜e了
The most recent Year
of the Rat was 1936.
最近的鼠年是1936
This is the key to
locker number 1936.
@就是ξ的a
- You're a very smart man.
- So was Abraham Lincoln.
你真明。
q如伯拉罕?林肯
Look what happened to him.
Smart can get you killed.
看看在他身上l生的事，由於明而被
I hope not.
我不希望在身上l生
Sometimes I feel I would like to...
有r我X得我想...
You'd like to what? Kiss me?
想啥？思春幔是想法式舌吻我？
Yeah, that would be nice.
如果是@幽蔷α耍我就是好@一口。
It would give me a chance to tell her I
was starting to feel something for her.
要是o我C我告V她，我_始感X到她
Something warm and squishy.
的囟群褴（我靠，@意淫的）
But a man in my business can't take
on a wife, have a bunch of kids.
但是就我@T在刀尖上行走的I，不能有妻子和一群孩子。
- We wouldn't have to have kids.
- What?
我不有孩子。
神R？
Look, this is getting us nowhere.
@我o可去
But thanks anyway.
但是要xx你
You'd better go now. Marlowe's
coming over here to talk.
你F在走吧，R湟砹
If you need me, just call.
如果你需要我，就打
You know how to dial, don't you?
你知道如何芴的，不是幔
You just put your finger in the
hole, and make tiny little circles.
用手指插M去，然後移有A圈。
Come on in. It's open.
M恚T_著。
Hello, Marlowe.
你好，R
Dammit. You didn't
do what I told ya.
死的。你]有打IВ老子e不是叮诹四懔幔
（此人楹喔トR?U嘉--Humphrey Bogart，@蚨碜 "In a Lonely Place")
I hate that dumb way of wearing
your shirt buttoned with no tie.
我你@N煞P的穿衣方式，r衫扣上最上面的扣子而不系IА
Let me get you a tie.
我o你挑一根
Here. This one's blue, but
you can wear it with brown.
就{色@l，但是你有穿的是棕色
- You annoy me.
- I annoy you?
你惹我生饬恕
蒸的？
You come in here with
no tie... Are you drunk?
你磉@e不系I...你喝酒了？
- How many have you had?
- One martini.
喝了多少斤？
一杯R蒂尼
- I knew I was gonna see you.
- Sit down.
我知道我要你
坐下
Here's what I want you to do.
我想你k@事。
Here's a list of names I found in a
bowl of soup. Don't ask me to explain.
我在一碗elF了@串名危不要我解
I think they're all dead.
I want you to check 'em out.
我想名紊系娜硕妓懒恕
我想你逐一_J一下是不是@印
And Marlowe? Put this on
for me, huh? As a favour.
有，系上@I，就是臀忙。
It's a clip-on.
@是便系式的。
I put Marlowe to work checking Kitty's
list against recent unsolved murders...
我一面R淙ブ鹨淮_J一下P蒂的名危ψ罱未解Q的\案
While I yellow-cabbed
it to the station...
c此同r，我打的去了火站。
To see how Dr Forrest's key
would fit into the puzzle.
去看看“中乳童他爹”留下的i}
I sashayed over to
locker number 1936.
我p的找的1936存。
The key fit like a glove.
As I opened the locker...
一打就_......
I noticed a handsome guy in a
grey pinstripe watching me.
我注意到一穿灰色ly西服的人在盯我的梢。
It seemed I wasn't the only one who was
interested in the contents of that locker.
看砦也皇俏ㄒ灰ξe有什N感d趣的人。
Inside were two long lists of
Carlotta's friends and enemies.
e面是LL的名危嚎洛塔的盟友和橙
The first name that jumped
out was FX Huberman...
第一名字是福克斯?胡伯曼
Number 46 Bay Court
Drive, Grunion Point.
（不知道到如何翻g@地址）
I decided to take a little train
ride and visit Mr Huberman.
我Q定坐火去@位胡伯曼
I knew "Handsome" would follow
me, so to throw him off...
我知道那位哥^m盯我的哨
I cleverly ducked into the
men's room and lost him.
所以我急中生智，去了男所，甩掉他。
There was no way he could follow me
unless I had toilet paper on my shoe.
世界上]有人能蚨⑽业纳遥除了我鞋上@l
Damn!
死的！
It wasn't really toilet
paper, it was a seat cover...
@他不是@l而是R桶w
But it was enough for a smart
guy to make the connection.
但@足以一明的人M行想
As soon as we went into a tunnel...
很快，火M了隧道
Handsome popped in and started
looking for a match... in my pockets.
那位哥@r突然出F，找他想要的|西，在我口袋e
- Oh! Was that your leg?
- No, it was my face.
哦，@是你的腿幔
不，是我的
I had no idea we were
going into a tunnel.
我不知道我一下就M隧道了
I'm sure.
我知道
I thought the
compartment was empty.
我以檫@包g是空的。
Yeah, right. Uh-huh, sure.
好吧，是@拥
00:29:17,300-> 00:29:18,658
（此人榧永?格m特--Cary Grant，@蚨碜 "Suspicion")
- I'm so sorry. I hope I didn't hurt you.
- It's all right.
我很抱歉，]有到你吧？
]毛事！
To what do I owe the
pleasure of your company?
你槭颤N磉@？（我欠你公司什N幔浚
The man in the next compartment's
smoking a vile cigar.
在下一有一吸雪茄的人
I had to come in here.
You don't smoke, do you?
所以我磉@海你不抽吧？
- No, I have tuberculosis.
- Oh, thank heavens for that.
Γ我有肺Y核。
哦，x天x地
After last night, my
head couldn't stand it.
自昨晚起，我的^都是的。
I didn't want him to know where I was
going so I decided to put him away fast.
我不想@哥知道我去哪e，所以我Q定把他“放倒”先！
I always carry my harmonica.
我是е我的口琴，我的“必⒓肌薄
It's lighter than an accordion, and
more powerful than a sleeping pill.
它比手L琴p，而且比丸更催人入眠。
I left him napping like a baby when
I ducked out at Grunion Point.
我他午睡的像小孩子一酉悖而我趁C下出站
Here's three bucks if you can get this
cab to 46 Bay Court in ten minutes.
我o你3美刀，如果你能在10分鹊46 Bay Court（B地名，不知道咋翻） 。
Follow that cab!
跟著前面那v出租！
It was a pretty clever thing I did.
我想了灰常不e的主x。
By taking the only two cabs, I made
sure Handsome couldn't follow me.
打了程，我想_J那哥]有出站再盯我的哨。
When I arrived at Mr
Huberman's, I was surprised.
到_休伯曼先生那e，我很意外
Mr Huberman turned out to be a sexy
dame who was throwing a party.
休伯曼先生原硎且性感的女人，正在主持一聚
She didn't even ask me what I wanted,
just made me feel real welcome.
她甚至]有我想要什N，只是我X得十分芤
（此人不用介B了：英格?褒曼--Ingrid Bergman，@蚨碜 "Notorious")
How about you, handsome? Haven't
I seen you somewhere before?
哥，玩的_d幔课是不是以前有^一面之？
Maybe. I've been somewhere before.
可能，我到^S多地方
It's nice of you to invite me.
I feel a little like a party crasher.
你@友我⒓泳， 真是太好了。
我就喜g不速之客擅J聚
I like party crashers.
@也正ξ业奈缚
I like classy dames
with bedroom eyes.
我喜g雅的女人和她撩人的眼神
You know something? I like you.
姐直f了吧，挺喜g你
I like me too.
我也挺欣p我自己的
When these people leave, maybe...
you and I can have a party of our own.
@些人x_後，你和我可以外加一霆享派Α
Oh, I... I have to think that over.
是幔我想@聚R上就Y束了。
She was a fast thinker.
@美女真硎隆
I'm very sorry. You all have to go.
It has been a perfectly hideous party.
我很抱歉，大家得x_了，今晚的聚完美的人@
- Good night.
晚安，晚安
Stuffy in here, isn't it?
岬牟恍校不是幔
Suddenly I realised she'd
slipped me a Mickey.
突然我意R到她o了我了饺肓嗣运的酒
My lips felt like two manhole covers.
My tongue felt like it had hair on it.
我的嘴唇感X像井w，我的舌^上好像有^。
My ears started to ring.
I felt like a dog.
我的耳朵_始起，我X得自己像l狗
Woof!
旺旺
Woof, Huberman, woof!
旺旺！休伯曼，旺旺！
Come on. Let's go out dancin'.
戆桑我去跳舞吧。
You put on your black dress,
and I'll go shave my tongue.
你去穿上你的黑色晚Y服，我去刮我舌苔
? Barbasol, Barbasol
巴巴索 巴巴索
? No brush, no lather, no rub-in
不刷不擦，]有泡沫
? Wet your razor then begin
呐衲愕奶甑度会衢_始
? Barbasol, Barbasol
巴巴索 巴巴索
? Oompah, oompah, oompah, oompah
典 典 典，，，，
Come on, FX. I'm ready!
戆桑海我浜昧耍
Let's go dancing.
我去v情歌舞吧
Hold it!
慢著！
Sorry, Dollface.
Σ黄穑中乳童。
- How did you get here?
- Your door was open, so I walked in.
你咋在@e？
你家T_著，我就M砹恕
- I've been trying to call you all night.
- How did I get here?
我整晚上都在o你打。
我是如何回@e的？
- I guess you must have crawled.
- Oh, God!
我猜你是爬回淼摹
我去！
- Oh, no, that's OK.
- It's just a little alcohol.
不，不，我@泳秃谩
我斫o你抹c酒精。
- They don't hurt.
- Don't be a baby.
我的腿]事。
不要像小孩子一优峦础
Get back!
後退！
What's up?
啥情r？
Sam Hastings is dead.
撒母耳?赫斯廷斯死了
Poor rummy. How did he get it?
可z的酒鬼，咋死的？
Fell out of a window reaching
for a bottle of whisky.
拇羯系粝恚伸手去拿一瓶威士卡
He could have been pushed. I'll have
Marlowe check his back for fingerprints.
他可能是被推下去的，我Rz查他的背部的指y。
- Anything else?
- Yes.
有e的事幔
有
I found another note
Daddy wrote to himself.
我找的了我爸的e的片
"NYTAG-216."
I think it's a New York
license plate number.
我想是~s牌的底
Not bad, Dollface.
Unless I'm... Ohh! Agh!
有M步，中乳童。
除非我。。。。。。。。。。
Careful. Let me get
you some alcohol.
小心，我o你擦c酒精
No!
不要
It's not N-Y TAG. It's N-Y-T.
@不是N-Y TAG，而是N-Y-T
New York Times.
~sr
So what's "A-G"?
哪"A-G"?
- Standard library talk for August.
- And 216?
斯坦_德D^8月v座
那216？
Stands for the August 2nd
issue, page one, column six.
代表8月2日的}，第一，第六
Extension 20, please.
Hi. It's me, Rigby.
是我，e格比
Sorry, Hot Legs, I've been busy.
Σ黄穑“L火”，我最近老是在外面跑。
You sashay over to your
New York Times file...
你快速“h到”你放~sr蟮牡胤...
Read me what's on page one, column
six of the August 2nd issue...
臀铱匆幌拢旱谝豁，第六冢8月2日的}
Maybe I'll wine and dine
you some night soon.
也S我在某晚上和你共M晚餐
I'll wait.
我等著哦。
You'd wine and dine
her for information?
我在某晚上和她共M晚餐
Her? Him.
不是妹子，是大老骸
Yeah... Then read me
the whole article.
好，然後把整篇文章xo我
"Immer Essen".
伊默?埃森
Walter Neff's the owner.
沃特?确蚴谴主。
Thanks, Hot Legs.
I owe you a big one.
x了，“L火”，我欠你大基情。
Immer essen.
伊默?埃森
That means "always eating".
直g^砭褪牵嚎是在吃
- What language?
- German.
啥Z言。
德Z
It's also the name of a
South American cruise ship.
@名字好像南美的[在用
I know! When Sam Hastings and my
sister separated last July...
我知道了，在去年七月撒母耳?黑斯廷和妹妹分居前
He took a South American
tour on that ship.
他е我妹妹在那艘船上去南美[[
Very interesting.
有意思
Right after that tour, the
company canceled its cruises.
在那次旅行之後，公司取消其]０
Now Sam Hastings is dead.
可F在撒母耳?黑斯廷炝恕
- I don't see the connection.
- I don't either. That's what bothers me.
我]看出其中的仍诼M。
我也是，@就是困_我的原因。
（此人楹喔トR?U嘉--Humphrey Bogart，@蚨碜  "Dark Passage" )
Hello?
你好
- Who is it?
- This is Marlowe.
你是l？
我是R
Oh, hello, Mr Marlowe. Would
you hold a moment, please?
你好，R湎壬等一下。
- It's Marlowe.
- Good.
R
砹
Hello, Marlowe. Listen, don't check
out those unsolved murders right now.
R洌我f，F在不要查那些叶未Q的\案了。
Yeah? Why not?
好，槊？
I got something more important. You
ever had any dealings with Walter Neff?
我F在有更重要的事要你查，你以前c沃特?确虼蚪坏幔
Walter Neff. He runs a South
American cruise-ship company.
沃特?确颍以前跑南美[艇的公司
Good. Tell me about him.
有你的，fc情。
Cruises supermarkets
looking for blondes?
游超市正在招金女郎？
Good. I'll supply the blonde.
很好，我供金女郎的。
One other thing.
有件事
If Walter Neff leaves the country,
I may have to take a little boat ride.
如果沃特?确蛞x_美，我可能要跟著去。
If I do, stay off the booze. These
people we're dealing with are killers.
如果我去了，你得戒酒，我正在Ω兜倪@些人可都是⑹
Well, thanks for telling me.
Have a nice trip.
感x你的忠告，旅途愉快。
I may not leave right away,
but thanks anyway. And Marlowe?
我可能不R上x_，管他的，但是R洌
- You wearin' a tie?
- Goodbye.
你Я祟I幔
再
- What was that all about?
- Marlowe knows Neff.
情r如何？
R渲道一下P於确虻那r。
Says he's a pushover
for beautiful blondes.
正在招金尤物。
It means we need a female spy.
Q句f我需要一女g
Why not use me?
槭颤N不直接用我？
Sorry.
呵呵
You're not blonde enough.
你不蚪痼。
- I can always dye my hair.
- No dice, Dollface. You're a client.
我是染。
不行，中乳童。你是客簟
That's one thing I've learned about
clients. Dead ones don't pay their bills.
@是我W到的P於客舻囊患事。死人不付巍
Is that all you think of me?
你就是@印氨∏楣蚜x”的看待我的幔
Someone who pays you $10 a day?
一每日支付你10美元的，又你摸^咪咪的人幔
不⑺勒嫣剑但c客簟罢鹎椤！――R
That's right, Dollface. To me
you're just a meal ticket.
是的，中乳童，你Y就是我的票。
How could I tell her
that I was lying?
我怎N能告V她我在撒e？
I'd work for nothing just to watch
her hair bounce as she walked...
我呆的站著只是榭此的^大波浪，如同她行走起砩碜说u曳...
Smell her creamy skin, cradle
her head on my shoulder.
感受她滑的皮w，她的^靠在我的肩上r
Feel the slope of her waist,
the curve of her back...
感受她腰部的曲，背部的曲
And then gently caress
her two beautiful...
然後pp崦她的美......
（真心意淫oO限――吊z冰t茶）
I'm sorry.
Σ黄稹
I just don't like being
called a meal ticket.
我只是不喜ge人叫我票
As I started my search for a blonde spy, I
tried to get rid of the image of Juliet...
我_始ふ乙金g美女r，我D不去想茱~的幼印
Storming out of my office
with toothpaste on her shoes.
中乳童_出了我的k公室，鞋上е“intel牙膏S的牙膏”
First on my list was Monica Stillpond,
a bombshell who once told me...
我的第一x袷悄妮卡?斯多芬迪，e人告V我@狠角色
She would do anything for
anybody anywhere at any time.
她可以拳打南帝，_踢北丐，^撞|邪，奶翻西毒。
She was in the middle of
a fancy dinner party.
她正在一A的晚宴上。
But I couldn't waste time being
polite. I caught her attention.
但是我]有把rg浪M在政治演f上，我o她砹“指”
（此人榫S_妮卡?R克--Veronica Lake，@蚨碜  "The Glass Key" )
Coffee will be served in the
living room, Mr Madvig.
咖啡是在客d，RS先生
One thing about Monica: The words
"I can't" weren't in her vocabulary.
莫妮卡的一大特c是：有求必！
Monica, I want you to
do something for me.
莫妮卡，我想你去做c事情。
I can't.
我不能
I guess she had added them since
the last time I'd seen her.
我猜她落了，自奈疑洗我^她後。
The next one on my list was Doris
Devermont, an old flame of mine.
我的下一人x是桃莉z?多沃曼，我的一老炮友
With her I'd had the most honest
relationship I'd ever had with a woman.
自奈液退搞上就]有去碰^其他女人
The only thing I'd lied about was my
name. I'd told her I was Teddy Novak...
只是真名我]有告V她，我假Q我樘┑?Z瓦克
So she couldn't track me
down if I got her pregnant.
我是怕她言辛耍碚椅乙奶粉X。
Doris remembered me, naturally.
桃莉z得我
（此人樨蒂?大l斯--Bette Davis，@蚨碜  "Deception" )
How do you do, Mr Novak?
^得咋樱Z瓦克先生？
Mr Novak? No hugs, no kisses? We used
to flop into each other's arms, Doris.
Z瓦克先生？]有肀В]有H吻，我可是大疬^300回合的眩桃莉z。
Well, don't you think we really ought to
get to know each other all over again?
y道你不J槲真的再次t解彼此幔
It's only been five years. You were about
to serve me dinner when I had to leave.
@只是五年r光而已。我正要x_你r，你正槲渫聿汀
How stupid of me.
You must be famished.
我多愚蠢呀，你一定是I了。
I should have thought of it sooner.
I'll get some coffee and sandwiches.
我早想到的，我去弄c咖啡，三明治
Coffee and sandwiches.
咖啡，三明治
Now I remembered Doris's
famous stale-bread sandwiches.
我F在想起砹耍桃莉z很擅L做不新r的三明治
She'd buy day-old bread, then toast it
to cover up. I wonder if she's changed.
她I不太新r的I包，烤一下，掩w一下那股味道，我以樗改掉@T了。
The bread's none too fresh.
Shall I toast it?
I包不太新r，我要烤一下幔
No, thanks. I gave up
stale toast for Lent.
x了，我不要不新r的I包在大Sr
- Lent?
- Nothing.
大S
]事
Same old Doris.
是那熟悉的桃莉z
She used to get smoked turkey
so it would keep for months.
她^去常吃熏火u，@持m保存月
When it finally went bad,
she'd feed it to the maid.
u最Kr，她把它o女W吃
I had some smoked turkey. I guess the
cleaning woman had it for her lunch.
我其有一下熏火u，我猜我女虻漠午吃了
Oh, here's some p?té.
有K（法Z）
Cleaning woman.
女
Cleaning woman!
Cleaning woman! Cleaning woman!
女颍女
女颍∨颍
Sorry.
Σ蛔
I was too embarrassed to ask Doris for a
favour after I'd tried to strangle her...
真心太擂瘟耍我D掐死她，她忙...
So I went to the next name
in my little black book.
所以我去找下一人x
The blondest one on my list was a rich
society dame named Jimmi Sue Altfeld.
@是最金可人的一，也是上流社的女人，苊?K?阿特菲
I almost hated to use her - she was so
in love with me, it nearly made me sick.
我其不意使用她，她是如此的畚遥畚业缀踝我感到f心。
But business was more important.
但是正所^“生意如手足，女人如衣服”
I wined her and dined her
at the Plantation Club.
我她在普m泰申俱凡亢染瞥燥。
Then I made my move.
然後我x_
Last time we saw each other, I left you
alone sitting at a counter at Schwab's.
我最後一次面，我x_你r你一人坐在施瓦布的
（此人槔娜?特{--Lana Turner，@蚨碜  "Johnny Eager" )
yuan18-原字幕
- You don't hate me for that, do you?
- Of course I don't.
你不生我的獍桑幔
我]有
Good...
很好
I'd like to discuss
something with you.
我想和你c事情
- Where to?
- Take me home.
我F在去哪？
我家
There was no way I was gonna
take her home. Her father hated me.
我是不可能去她家的，他爸恨死我了
So I told her to meet me at a motel and
I'd show her something with my hands.
所以，我她砺灭^和我面，我她表演“手影秀”
Come in.
M
（此人槔娜?特{--Lana Turner，@蚨碜  "The Postman Always Rings Twice" )
Well, Jimmi Sue, you ready?
好了，可人海浜昧幔
What are we going to do?
我接下碜錾耨R？
Kinsey from cover to cover.
做c成人做的氖隆
Has anyone ever told you that your lips
are like two succulent Brussels sprouts...
有人f^你的p唇像多汁的布塞幼芽幔
- ...waiting to be buttered and bitten?
- Plenty of men have.
需要S油滋和p咬
很多男人都有
Really?
真的？
Have these men ever told you...
@些人曾告V^你
that your eyes are like Chinese coins
with dollops of caviar in the center?
你的眼睛像中XеK~子u色的中心？
Can't you see how happy
you and I would be here?
你看不出有多幸福幔
你和我在@e？
Yes, I do. But I want you to come
back to the city with me first.
是的，我能感受到，但是我希望你和我先回到城e。
I'm working on an important case. It's
dangerous, and you'll probably be killed.
我手e有一重要的案子，很危U，你也可能被.
- But if you love me, you'll do it.
- Yes, I do love you.
但是，如果你畚业脑，你去的。
是的，我勰恪
And I love you. And I mean that more
than anything I've ever said in my life.
我勰悖龠^畚易约旱纳命。
@是什N鬼指型？――六}神Γ浚
I rented an apartment and started giving
Jimmi instructions on how to pump Neff.
我租了一套公寓，_始o苊劢榻B确虻那r
She took direction like
a pig takes to garbage.
她根本就不是做女g的料。
Here's a picture of our Mr Neff.
@是确虻恼掌
Do, uh, whatever you have to...
哦，o如何你必
To find out what happened
on the Immer Essen.
找出在伊默?埃森上l生了什N
Your father threatened to have me
beat up if I continue to see ya.
你父H威{要修理我，如果我^m和你搞在一起。
Thought I'd drop over there tomorrow
with a little peace offering.
我想明天我用c和平的方法斫Q@}。
What could I take
that'd soften him up?
我能拿什N碥化他？
He never had a dog
when he was a boy.
他小r候]有B^狗。
Never had a dog, huh?
]有B^狗？
（此人鄣氯A?阿Z德--Edward Arnold，@蚨碜  "Johnny Eager" )
Mr Altfeld?
阿特菲德先生？
Totally house-broken.
“乾Q房g――破恼摺
His name is... Ramon.
他名字叫，雷蒙
He's yours.
他是你的了
Get out, thief!
L出起，小偷
I'm not stealing your daughter. I'm just
borrowing her for an important case.
我不是硗底吣闩旱模我是借她磙k一案子的。
Don't go near my daughter. Don't try to
see her. Don't write and don't phone.
不准你靠近她！看她！信o她！打o她！反正不准！
Can I use her underwear
to make soup?
那我可以拿她的纫妊煮幔
- Get out!
- Mr Altfeld...
鬼出去！
阿特菲德先生...
By helping me, your
daughter's life is in danger.
在椭我r，你女旱纳命於危U之中。
But she may save hundreds of lives.
You wouldn't stand in the way of that.
但是她可能挽救上百l生命。你不能@嗳嘶盥
Why certainly I would!
我一定的
I'd frame you or kill you... if
it would protect my daughter.
老子弄死你就是榱吮Ｗo好我女骸
And I brought you a puppy,
something you never had as a boy.
我I了小狗，是榱舜幽恪
Now get out!
F在L出去
Come on, Ramon.
戆桑雷蒙
You don't deserve a puppy.
你不配B@小狗
Wait!
站住
Pick that up.
把@熳
- But it's all soft and steamy.
- Pick that up!
但是@又又瘛
so熳
You're a sick man, Altfeld.
你真尼人f心，阿特菲德
You can make me pick up dog dirt, but
you can't stop me seeing Jimmi Sue.
你能我熳吖肥海但是不能我不去你女骸
- You want a puppy?
- I'd love a dog.
你想要@只小狗幔
我就是喜g小狗。
Thank you.
xx
- Here's something for you, too.
- Oh, thank you.
@也o你。
xx
Eugh!
雅叮f心！
Well, Larry, Moe and Curly.
@尼好，拉e，莫伊，克雷
（此人榭驴?道格拉斯--Kirk Douglas，@蚨碜  "I Walk Alone" )
Thanks, Dan.
x了，丹
Not a nice way to treat a friend
of Mr Altfeld's daughter.
@不是Υ阿特菲德女号栌训挠押梅椒ā
There's only one way to treat you.
@e只有一N方法Υ你。
You got some pretty
smart monkeys here.
@e有一些很明的猴子
I notice this one's wearing
a Phi Beta Kappa key here.
我注意到在@@e有一穿著a Phi Beta Kappa key的。
- Ow!
- Your move.
去
你放大招了。
I'm gonna have some
sense beaten into you.
我有些土P你快感。
What's he payin' you boys? I'll double
it and we'll beat the shit outta him.
什N是他o你的孩子？我p倍o你，我一起@煞P，然後你跟我混。
瞬gL鼻子哥哥！！！
果然是“躺真探”，R要口，打不手，混你妹了。
最後“身清蒸SF”的。
Rigby?
e格比
我去，“]山升霸”盲狙炮友，值钠亮，加10分。
Juliet!
茱~
Those dirty bastards!
Beating up a woman.
av的混蛋打女人。
They even knocked your
breasts out of whack.
他甚至把你的中咪咪震出胸罩了。
Rigby?
e格比
Juliet... Are you all right?
茱~，你]事吧？
Oh!
Yes, I'm fine.
]事
- You look awful.
- It's all in a day's work.
你看起O牧恕
是呀 ，整天都在忘我的查案。
No, Rigby. It's not worth it.
不能@樱e格比，不值得！
- I want you to quit.
- Why? Because I've been roughed up?
我想你不要查@案子了。
槊？因槲被群了？
You've also been
shot and drugged...
你是被躺，又是被下迷....
And probably had to go to bed
with women you didn't know.
你可能和你不JR女人炮鹨话倩睾喜幌禄鹁。
You're just upset about
me interviewing blondes.
你F在在心我和我要面的金美女s炮。
You can forget about it.
少吃c地嫌停少操c中南海的心，好吧。
（以前也抽，@招可是c神技哦）
I've decided to get the
information myself.
我自己去搞Y的。
How?
如何搞？
By disguising myself
as a beautiful blonde.
去趟泰，立R搞定。
- Do I look like a dame?
- Not as much as I do.
我像美女幔
有c吧
- I haven't turned on the charm yet.
- Rigby, I wish you'd let me go instead.
我]有_Ⅶ攘Πl}模式。
e格比，我希望你能我去
Have Neff try and feel you up?
No chance, Dollface.
确虮M情的上你？
]可能，中乳童。
Oh. You don't want
Mr Neff to feel me up?
你不想确蛏衔遥
That doesn't mean you're beginning
to... care for me, does it?
Q句f就是你想霸我了，不是幔
I don't want any of
my clients felt up.
我不想和我的客簟捌呱习讼隆
I'm late. Neff cruises supermarkets
every Thursday looking for blondes.
我要完了，确蜻[超市在每星期四招聘金美女
If I'm half the woman
I think I am...
如果有一c女人味的，我想
I'll have a date with
Neff by tonight.
我和确蛟诮裢砑s
Good luck.
祝你好h。
Neff's favourite hunting ground
was Jerry's Market on Melrose.
确蜃钕gs炮的地方是在梅_斯的苎e的大市
I spotted him right away and sidled
down the aisle opposite him.
我J出他了，KR上移向他γ娴倪^道
I was wearing a special
perfume called "Fondle Me".
我用了一N叫：“嵛摇钡南闼
Its aroma drew Neff to me
like fat to a mother-in-law.
它的香味吸引了确颍其X得我是一“狼虎之年K乾柴烈火V鑫璐”。
He was a ladies' man, all right.
He made me feel beautiful, alive.
他是好男人，他我X得美且活著
He asked me up to his place,
and I didn't play hard to get.
他邀我到他家，我就@虞p易的手了。
All right.
好吧
On his home ground, Neff was more
aggressive and I played along.
在他家e，确蚝臀彝娴母是HI!
“我去，尼口味好重，不m人群F在可以快M一小段了。”
- I'm crazy about you, baby.
- I'm crazy about you too, Walter.
我被你的岽襟@住了，好害，情鄣模。
我也被你的岽襟@住了，好Ц校情鄣模。
That perfume.
What's the name of it?
@N香水。
啥名字的f？
"Fondle Me".
嵛
Silly!
西利
That's the name of the perfume.
那是香水的名字
- I feel like a drink.
- All I've got is bourbon.
我想喝一杯
我@e全是波本威士卡
I'll make the drinks.
我去{c酒
Sit over there.
稍安勿躁
（此人楦トR德?克莫瑞--Fred MacMurray，@蚨碜  "Double Indemnity" )
I wanted to knock him out fast. I slipped
him 15 milligrams of Aphrodisiamil...
我想揍他一D。我o他15毫克的迷
And hoped it would take effect
before he tried to pick my lock.
在他Dc我pd啪啪啪之前，希望迷生效
Sorry, Walter. That's as far
as I go on a first date.
不好意思，沃特，我第一次s就搞成@印
I didn't know what I was looking
for, but what I found was dynamite.
我不知道找什N，但是我s找到疟的|西
The passenger list of the
Immer Essen's final cruise.
是埃森最後的]乘客名
It was the same as the
Carlotta "Enemies" list.
@是同邮强洛塔的“橙恕泵
One name rang a bell. Cody Jarrett,
captain of the Immer Essen.
一名字人眼前一亮，科迪 Z勒特，永h的埃森的船L
I went to the public library and looked
up everything I could on Captain Jarrett.
我想去公共D^，t解Z勒特船L的一切
（yuan18--原字幕）
"Framed Because He Knew Too Much."
_陷，因樗知道太多
"But He Refuses to Divulge What He
Knew to Anyone but His Mother."
他拒^透露他所知道的o任何人，他母H除外
I hoped to find out why the passengers
on the Immer Essen's final cruise...
我希望能找到原因，槭颤N埃森]最後一次航行的乘客
Were being knocked off one by one.
一都被值
They all must have seen
something. But what?
他一定是看到什N，但是到底是什N乃？
What do you think?
我看起硐“老帷保
I think you enjoy
dressing up as a woman.
我想你是自我感X良好太多了c
Jarrett's mother's the only
visitor he'll talk to.
好吧，中乳童
Z勒特的母H，是他唯一跟他f的人
And I think I look enough like her
to get a gift on Mother's Day.
我想我已打扮的足蛳衲赣Ho他Y物的母H了
Rigby, wait!
e格比，慢著
Don't... don't call me Rigby.
不要叫我的真名
I'm worried. Since you
were beaten up...
我心你，自纳洗文惚蝗後
I've had nightmares about
something awful happening to you.
我曾做^噩簦可怕的事l生在你身上
I care about you, Rigby.
我在乎你，e格比。
What?
神R
I care about you.
我真心在乎你
What's the matter?
咋了
You. You're the matter.
是你的}
Did... did I... do something wrong?
我做e了什N？
Yeah. You crept into my gut.
是，你偷走我的心。
You've got me thinking silly thoughts,
like... hanging up my gun for good.
你我MX子的愚蠢想法，就像…r常要注意子拉拉好
Becoming a one-woman guy.
成一[寡嗟哪腥
Settling down in an
ivy-covered cottage...
悠f的坐在常春藤覆w平房下...
Raking leaves out
of the backyard...
把淙~尼嵩喊页...
Squeezing orange juice
for you in the morning.
早上榨橙汁o你。
You'd do that for me?
你意槲易鲞@些？
- Yeah, I would.
是的
- Oh, Rigby.
哦：H上的，H下的，H左的，H右的，H到指^尖尖的e格比。
哦，尼街搞女基，被深深震@到了。
Cody Jarrett's mother.
科迪 Z勒特的母H。
（此人檎材匪?Z克--James Cagney，@蚨碜  "White Heat" )
Hello, Ma.
。
My name is Reardon. I have
important news for you.
我叫里D，有重要Yo你
So just pretend I'm your ma, OK?
就我你。
The paper said you were hit in the head
by a flying wrench in the machine shop.
蠹上f你被C器g的一w扳手撞到了^上
Friends of Carlotta are after
you because you know too much.
因槭强洛塔的盟友值模你知道的太多
- I see what you mean.
- So the flying wrench was no accident.
啥意思
你受那不是意外
For a minute I thought it was.
等等，我想一下。
Something like that may
happen again, so...
有可能那“意外”再次重F。
The guard looks suspicious.
Act like I'm your ma.
警l生疑了，快b的我像是你。
- Sure.
- Pretend I'm crying. You comfort me.
好的
假b我在哭泣。你安慰我。
Relax, Ma.
放，
Say something like, uh,
"No, no, Ma. Look, listen to me."
快@诱f，不不不不，我f，
No, no, Ma. Look, listen to me.
不不不不，我f，
That was good. Real good.
演的不e，真不粗。
Look, as long as the other
prisoners can get to you...
只要行吹娜四苷业侥
You're not safe. But don't
worry, I have a plan.
你就等著彀桑但是我湍悖不要心
I contacted Warden Dudley,
who owed me a favour.
我M了典zL杜德利，他欠我一人情
I asked him to let me pose as a prisoner
so I could keep an eye on Jarrett...
我他我囚犯，@游揖涂梢员OZ勒特了
Maybe learn something
about Carlotta.
可能我能知道一些P於卡洛塔的事
I learned fast. Jarrett had a prison
break planned that very night.
我t解的太快，Z勒特在深夜的越z
I was invited along... at gunpoint.
When they stuffed me in the trunk...
我也在其中之列.是在口下威逼下，他把我扔M了的後湎洹
I realised he was a friend of
Carlotta, and I was their enemy.
我意R到他是卡洛塔的盟友，而我是他的橙
Ryley, you get in the front.
And you, you drive.
利，你去前，你去_。
I bounced along in that
trunk a long time.
我在的後湎溲e一“承上⑾隆边\印
Five hours later, I had given up hope of
ever going to a regular bathroom again.
5小r後，我被得再也不想去普通浴室了
I decided to have a little
chat with Captain Jarrett.
我Q定和Z勒特船L聊一
Hey, Cody!
科迪
- How are you doing', partner?
- I can't breathe.
合作夥伴，你咋樱
我快TM憋死了。
Oh. Stuffy, huh?
岚桑
- I'll give you a little air.
- Thanks.
我你出硗竿狻
xx。
P去，@次直接上：“吸星大法，第九重――“唇X真Next”
Her lips were warm, and my arm wasn't
the only thing that was throbbing.
她的t唇是如此暖潮，我除受的的手臂，全身哪e都在“激印
Our hearts were, too.
包括我心中的小鹿。
My plan was to kiss her with
every lip on my face...
我本想吻遍她的烈焰t唇的“犄角旮旯骸......
Then slowly move her to the next room,
maneuver her next to the bed...
然後慢慢地把她抱到隔壁房g，在床放下，之後再H手y其乳量...
Marry her, and start
the whoopee machine.
接著撩拙洌最後_足R力装l。
My plan was working fine until...
我的很SM，F好尼“wC觥
Agh! You stuck your
finger in my bullet hole.
啊！你摸到我的口了。
- Sorry, Rigby.
- I'll be all right.
Σ黄穑。
我]事
Why don't you lie down?
你槭颤N不躺下恚
I'll go to the drugstore and get
you something for your arm.
我R上去s店Ict治你手臂的回怼
It's raining too hard.
Call a cab. Hurry back.
雨好大，打吧，速去速回。
I feel like kissing somebody.
我想在好想要。。。。。。
Don't start without me.
“不准自己用手解Q，等我回怼！
Hello?
l？
- It's me, Margaret.
- Who?
我是格特。
l碇？
- Margaret.
- Margaret?
格特
格特？
Margaret Croyden.
格特 克诘
Margaret Croyden?
I don't believe it!
格特 克诘牵
真的？
- I don't believe you'd call me.
- I'd have called sooner...
我不相信你o我打
我早就o你打了
- You shouldn't call at all.
- It's so quiet here.
你不打
@e很安o的可怕。
（此人榄?克陴--Joan Crawford，@蚨碜  "Humoresque" )
Oh, Victor's gone for
the weekend, huh?
哦，S克托去度L末了，孤了是吧？
Sorry. Not interested.
我F在δ]有性趣。
Because I'm in love.
Yeah, really in love.
因槲椰F在有了真邸
Γ蒸邸
A few days ago I said something to
a woman I thought I'd never say.
一段rg恚我f了些]有其它女人f^的。
I actually said "I want to settle down
in an ivy-covered cottage with you..."
我真心的f：“我想和你一起住在常春藤覆w的小屋e
Rake leaves out of the backyard...
把淙~尼嵩喊页...
"... squeeze orange juice
for you in the morning."
早上榨橙汁o你
I spoke to Victor. He'll
give me the divorce.
我oS克托f了。他o我x婚。
I'll tell you what. Come down
tomorrow. We'll drive back together.
我有一k法。明天就k。我一起_回去
Wonderful! I can't wait to come
bouncing back into your life again.
太好了！我迫不及待地想再次回到你的生活中
No dice, Margaret. Call
me in another 12 years.
]T，格特，12年後再o我打。
All right, darling.
好吧，H鄣
- Hello?
- Mr Reardon...
喂
里D先生
I have decided to close this
case as of this moment.
我F在Q定不再o你做@@案子了。
A check will be in the
mail for you tomorrow.
M用明天寄o你支票的。
Please do not try to contact me as
I will be out of town for some time.
不要再砺M我，我R上x_@e
Juliet, has someone got
a gun to your head?
茱~，有人用威{你幔
Juliet!
茱~
A half-bottle of bourbon later
I still couldn't believe it.
著喝了半瓶波旁威士卡後，我是o法相信@突
Was Juliet crazy like her sister?
茱~被才的大雨淋感冒而掉了？就像她那失心妹妹？
Had she fallen in love with the cab
driver on the way to the drugstore?
是在去s店的路上和程司C“震定情”了
Or was she a member of the Carlotta
conspiracy and had set me up?
或是她是卡洛塔的\中的一T，ｉT^硗媾我的感情的？
Finally, I arrived at a
very important conclusion.
最K我得出了一重要的Y。
Shit on her!
我去她娘H的！
All dames are alike.
所以女人都善，都碜造短┨剐乔颉
They reach down your throat,
grab your heart... and pull it out.
她把手伸到你的喉担抓住你的心房…把它拔出怼
They throw it on the floor... and they
step on it with their high heels.
她把它扔在地板上…用高跟鞋踩著它。
They spit on it, shove it in the
oven, then cook the shit out of it.
她吐口水在上面，把它推到烤箱e，然後把它拿出碇蟆
They slice it into little pieces,
slam it on a hunk of toast...
她把它切成小K，M一大KI包
And they serve it to ya.
然後o你吃。
They expect you to say "Thanks,
honey, it's delicious."
她希望你f“xx”，
H鄣模很好吃
Well, it's not delicious,
Juliet Forrest.
嗯，但@不好吃，
茱~?福里斯特
It's rotten.
是臭的。
I don't give a damn if
I ever hear from you again.
如果我能再到你的音，我一c也不在乎。
- Juliet?
- This is Alan.
茱~?
艾
Alan?
艾？
- Come on, Marlowe, no games.
- I never could fool you, could I?
不要@樱R洌不要_玩笑。
我以前有欺_你，我有幔
（此人楹喔トR?U嘉--Humphrey Bogart，@蚨碜 "archive footage")
No.
是的
Listen, Marlowe.
好好著，R
Juliet left me, and...
茱~我而去....
I feel like I've been hit
with a wet frying pan.
我心如郝C哼^一
How the hell do you
pick up the pieces?
你是怎N@N情r的？
I'm beginning to realise it's better
to have something to look forward to.
要是我的，我就R上向前看。
"Look forward to." Like what? Work?
向前看？用工作淼窒^去？
I can't get a break on this case.
我不能@案子中途而U
I don't even know who the
hell this Carlotta dame is.
我甚至不知道l是卡洛塔夫人。
Can you get a map of South America?
你手上有南美的地D幔
- Yeah. You got something?
- Look up Peru.
可以，你用碜錾叮
R上找秘
Got it!
找到了
There's a little town on
the coast called Paita.
有一小海I城市叫派塔（秘西北部港市）
Tell me where it is.
告V我在哪e。
It's right next to a tiny
little island called...
就在一小u旁，叫...
You son of a gun! Carlotta!
尼的戈壁！卡洛塔！
Damn! It's not a woman's name.
死！@不是女人的名字。
It's a place.
是地名。
- Thanks, Marlowe. I owe ya.
- Good.
x了，R洌我欠你一人情。
很好。
I'm leaving for Carlotta right now.
我R上就去那e。
Even if Juliet's gone, I'm
gonna solve this case...
即使茱~走了，我也要解Q@案子
No matter how many killers are
involved, even if Juliet's one of 'em.
不管有多少⑹衷谀旱戎，即使中乳童也是他的⑹帧
Any idea where in Carlotta
I should start looking?
在卡洛塔有什N索需要我去查幔
There's a little café
right on the bay.
在海秤疫有小咖啡^
When I arrived, I thought of the words
Marlowe had said to me 15 years ago:
我到_的r候，我想起了，R湓15年前曾ξ艺f^的。
"Dead men don't wear plaid."
死人是不穿格子花呢的。
Huh!
哼！
Dead men don't wear plaid.
死人是不穿格子花呢的。
I still don't know what it means.
我至今不能理解其意。
Carlotta was the kind of town where
they spell trouble T-R-U-B-I-L...
卡洛塔是混s著各N麻┑某鞘
and if you try to correct
them, they kill you.
如果你想改@一切，那你就玩完了。
（此人榘娃?加德{--Ava Gardner，@蚨碜 "The Bribe")
I knew Marlowe had
steered me right.
R溆胁倏匚业嗬。
There was Kitty Collins, the girl
who ditched me in Santa Barbara.
是P蒂?柯林斯，那在}巴巴拉逃避我的女孩
（也是我心中女神他爹的心中女神）
Se?or Reardon.
里D
Manuel Alesandro.
曼~?焉５铝_
Not quite.
不蚀_
Carlos Rodriguez.
卡洛斯?_德里格斯
- Carlos Rodriguez?
- Sí.
卡洛斯?_德里格斯？
是的
Before the war... we ran
guns to the rebels.
在爆l前，我向叛射簟
Oh, yeah.
有@事
You're a cop.
F在你是T警了
Sí, sí, sí.
是的，是的，是的，
I have joined the establishment.
我加入了嗯
That's good, Carlos. I'm here on an
investigation. Maybe you can help me.
很好，卡洛斯，我磉@e是榱苏{查一案子，也S你能助我一臂之力。
There is much to
investigate in Carlotta.
卡洛塔就是~混s的地方。
The whole island is
like a powder keg.
整u就是一火桶
There is much tension, the...
the smell of something rotten.
@e夥站o，漫著腐的味道。
That's what I'm here for. To
find out what it is that smells.
我就是檫@恚找出槭颤N有腐的味道
Psst!
u
Be careful of the, uh,
fat one who sweats a lot.
小心那人，出汗很多的胖子
（此人椴槔硭?陬D--Charles Laughton，@蚨碜 "The Bribe")
What about Kitty Collins?
P蒂?柯林斯是啥色？
She doesn't sweat as much,
but she's just as dangerous.
她K不是看起砟印疤鹈揽煽谇宜多如注”，反倒是危U角色。
They say she is one of them.
他都是她是他一夥的。
Who is... "them"?
他都是哪？
Nobody knows. Only they
know who is "them".
]人知道，只有他知道他是什N。
But there is a man. His
name is Arroz. Rice.
不^有人，名叫阿_斯?斯
Kitty Collins is in love with him.
P蒂?柯林斯是他的A情炮友.
He is a killer.
他是⑹
- Rice, huh?
- Uh-huh.
斯，呵？
嗯
- Thanks, Carlos.
- De nada, se?or.
x了，卡洛斯
不客
- Where are you staying?
- Hotel Guano.
你F在住在哪e？
瓜Z酒店。
Ha! I'll be in touch.
我回碚夷愕
Cuidado, Se?or Reardon.
致敬，里D
Cuidado, Carlos... Cuidado.
致敬，卡洛斯
I wanted Kitty Collins to
tell "them" I was in town...
我想在城e，要P蒂?柯林斯告V我P於“他”是什N
So I tossed a five-pesetaria
coin into the bowl.
所以我打p5pesetaria硬拧
The clank was loud enough
to make her look my way.
想硬怕淙胪胫械亩吸引她的注意K向我@看。
That five-pesetaria coin was the
best investment I ever made.
5pesetaria硬攀俏夷茏龅淖詈猛顿Y
The next day, I hooked a big fish:
A fat one who sweats a lot.
第二天，我了一l大~，那出汗很多的胖子
- Se?or?
- Nothing alcoholic. Oh, a beer, maybe.
不要任何酒水，算了，睃c啤酒吧
Sí, se?or.
R上就
Hard liquor goes to my feet.
烈酒流恚我楹我拒。
Just a minute, Mr Rigby.
等等，e格比先生
We know who you are, Mr Rigby.
我t解你，e格比先生
I'm interested. Who am I?
我很感d趣，你都t解啥？
You could be a guy
who collects $10,000...
你可能是那@得1f美刀的那人
Just to leave this stinkin' town.
然後x_@的城市
- I could, could I?
- You know who I could be?
我是幔
你知道我是l幔
Hunchback of Notre Dame?
枪秩耍
I could be the guy who
hands ya... them $10,000.
我可能是那o你1f美刀的那人
$10,000. Me to you...
just like that.
1f美刀，我o你，如此p
Sorry. My price for leaving
stinking towns is 11,500...
Σ黄穑我x_臭城的代r是11,500...
And a kiss on the lips
from Carmen Miranda.
外加要和卡T?米m_“唇鹕嗑d震春浴
Pass it on to "them". Room 204.
o他，我在204房等。
Room 204, se?ora.
204房，小姐
Come in.
M。
Right on time, Kitty.
Been expecting ya.
你很r，P蒂，我一直在等你
Thought you'd come last night.
以槟阕蛲
- I wasn't thinking too well last night.
- Keep talking.
我昨晚有不太好的感X。
f砺。
You see, I just found
out something, Rigby.
e格比，我lF了些}。
Who you are, what you do,
and why you're in Carlotta.
你是哪？想质颤N？槭颤N要砜洛塔
I'm here to bust up your game.
我磉@eY果你
I don't get it. A class girl like you
in love with a killer like Rice.
我想不明白，像你@雅端f的女孩槊喜g一像斯@拥⑹帧
Who... what... why?
檎l...樯耨R...槊？
When you love someone...
你真勰橙r
I guess it doesn't make any
difference who, what or why.
我猜你也不在乎他是l，致锏模槭颤N。
You go right on loving them.
你xo反去鬯。
Yeah, you do, don't ya?
Γ你@A情做了，Π
I feel as if...
我想...
Make me another drink,
will you, baby?
再o我硪槐料，好幔可人？
Hello?
喂
- What's up, amigo?
- Plenty.
怎N了，朋友?
重磅消息。
A plane arrived today, and all
the passengers spoke German.
一架wC今天到_@e，乘客全是f德Z的。
- German?
- Mm-hm. Our friend Rice was there.
德人？
Γ斯也在那e
They gave him a packet.
It was marked today's date...
他o他包裹。
要今天成交
- ...and "Final Instructions".
- How do you know?
和“最後的指示”
你槊知道？
I was hired to protect Rice until he
gets on that plane with Kitty Collins...
我被派去保o斯和P蒂?柯林斯，直到他上wC
Tonight after the
Carlotta Festival.
在今晚卡_塔之後
Why are you telling me this?
槊告V我@些重要热
Because the lives of
millions of innocent p...
因樯婕暗蛋偃fo辜的生命
Carlos? Carlos!
卡洛斯？卡洛斯？
Carlos!
卡洛斯！
Damn.
死的
Where are you and
Rice headed tonight?
今晚你和斯去哪e？
What do you know about a
plane with Germermans on it?
P於德人的包C你都知道些什N？
Germerm... Germans.
德...德人
Germermans.
德人
There's a plane with mermans on it.
德人的包C
The plane's in town.
@wC到了@e
Ethel Merman came in on it.
艾瑟?默曼碓谶@
Wanna go see Ethel Merman with me?
想和我一起去看艾瑟?默曼幔
I'll buy two tickets.
我I了票
Let me get on my pajamas,
I'll be ready to go.
我穿上睡衣，我浜昧怂X了
I'd done some brilliant
things in my time.
我做了件傻逼的事
Asking Kitty Collins to mix me
a drink wasn't one of them.
P蒂?柯林斯o我倒酒，便其有Co我下迷。
When I came to, I could make out
only light and shadow at first.
我醒^r，我只能先看到模糊的光和影。
Then I saw an unfamiliar face.
But even in my stupor...
然後我看到一陌生的。但即使在我的昏迷中
I knew he was one of the big
fish in the conspiracy: Rice!
我也知道他是@\中的大人物之一，斯！
（此人槲纳特?普R斯--Vincent Price，@蚨碜 "The Bribe")
Well, I believe that
about winds things up.
哦，我相信P於F在流髂愕氖铝
- I'm gonna wind you up on a rope.
- But you're the one who's gonna die.
我要用K子把你拴起矸棚L~。
但你是那死去的人
Better make it look good. If anything
fishy happens to me, the FBI...
最好把我窝b成自然死亡，不然FBI追查我的非常死亡的...
It'll look very natural.
@看起硎亲匀凰劳龅摹
People who know Rigby Reardon know
I'd never die a natural death.
JR我，e格比?里D的人都知道我不是自然死亡的。
Do you think I'd leave
you around to talk?!
你J槲疫留著你你f出情幔
You've already talked too much!
你已f的蚨嗔耍
Hold it, Rice!
e起手恚斯
You're not getting on that plane
tonight. I want those papers.
你今晚上不了wC了，我要那些n。
I'm gonna walk out of
this room. You won't shoot.
我你不敢_，我x_@g屋子r。
I won't?
我不敢？
That was a warning shot, Rice. And I
don't fire as many of 'em as I used to.
那是一警告，斯。我才不像^去那些人一硬婚_反簟
Rigby! Se?or!
e格比！
- I heard shots.
- I'm all right.
我到。
我]事。
- Rice went that way.
- Come on, Carlos!
斯想_溜。
快追，卡洛斯！
Are you wearing pajamas?
Se?or, I'll help you take them off.
你穿的是睡衣幔
我湍忝了它。
I don't need help with
my pajamas! Stop!
我不需要你臀颐!
- Sí.
- Carlos!
卡洛斯!
Sí. Don't worry about your
pajamas, se?or. I'll take care of them.
不要管你的睡衣，我保管它。
Out of the way! We are
chasing a killer!
L_！我在抓词郑
Everybody stand back! He's with me.
大家退後！跟我
Coming through!
D^去！
Cuidado, se?or. Cuidado!
停下！停下！
- Stand back!
- Cuidado!
退後！停下！
Se?or! Your pajamas!
你的睡衣！
Forget the pajamas!
不要管我的睡衣，煞P！
- Are you all right?
- It's just a bullet.
你咋樱
不就是中了w“花生米”幔
My wife Carmelita will suck
it out. Go ahead, se?or.
我的妻子卡梅莉塔吸出淼模快去追！
（我操，此片e的女人都是^吸星大法的）。
And don't worry about your
pajamas. I'll take care of them!
不要管你的睡衣，我保管好的！
"Final Instructions".
最後的指示
（^密）
So that's their game.
@就是最KBoss，Π伞
"Rasmussen Place".
拉斯R森?普R斯。
The last thing I expected to see was
Juliet and her father, alive...
我期待中乳童和她父H活著...
Talking with their butler, who
was dressed in a Nazi uniform.
而且正和他的管家在，管家穿著{粹党l-w世太保的制服
Yeah. That explained a lot.
一切真相大白。
Why Juliet was able to translate
German, for one thing.
槭颤N茱~能蛉绱司通德Z。
I'd been played for a sucker.
我被小耍了，像煞P一印
But it wasn't too late
to set things straight.
但是事不宜t，我y反正一把！
Yaaah!
哥砹相！
OK, hands in the air.
Over on the steps. Let's go!
好吧，各位e起手恚站到_A上去，快c！
It's time for a class picture. Tall
ones in back, short ones in front.
上nrg到了。後面站高的，前面站矮的。
Now sit! Hold hands.
F在坐下，恐手。
Now smile.
微笑。
- That's nice.
- Rigby...
很好。
e格比...
Hold it! Stay where you are,
you dirty, lying Nazi scum.
e起手恚站住！
你@eB篇的“{粹共用诬”。
Rigby!
e格比
I should have known. I fell for a
dame who played me for a sucker.
我早知道了。我凵狭艘玩弄我感情的女人。
No, Mr Reardon. She did not
play you for a sucker.
不，里D先生，她K]有小耍你。
I did. Pretending to be a butler, waiting
on inferior races was galling to me.
是我做的，假扮管家，侍奉劣等民族的使我感到馈
- But I fooled everyone.
- You see, Rigby? I didn't betray you.
但我愚弄了每人。
你看，e格比？我]有背叛你。
- How did you know to come here?
- Marlowe told me.
你咋知道磉@e？
R涓嬖V我的。
That's how I found Daddy.
I smelled his cheese molds.
我就是@诱业桨职值
我到了他做的乳酪q菌味道。
I am sorry to interrupt
such a tender scene...
我很抱歉，打嘁幌逻@厝岬男【...
But we have a plan
to carry out now.
因槲F在有一要施
- Who are you really, kraut?
- Field Marshal Wilfred von Kluck.
泡}N，敢真名？
威弗雷德?T?克拉克元。
- At your service.
- Von Kluck?
槟效冢
T?克拉克？
Former chief of Hitler's
Special Secret Weapons Corps.
前希特勒特e秘密武器F人。
I'm flattered. How did you know?
^了，你如何知道？
I figured out your
whole stinking scheme.
我想通了你的整臭。
How you duped Dr Forrest into helping
you. How you flew in your agents!
你如何欺_福里斯特博士椭你。你如何忽悠你的代理人！
The finest officers
in the Führer's army.
最秀的菲雷部官
- Former army.
- For the moment.
前！
那是r的。
But we shall rise again.
但我⒃俅吾绕
- We'll see about that.
- How did they use Daddy?
我看到的。
他是如何利用我爸的。
Bullet-head here found out your father
had developed a cheese mold...
最保守的{粹分子lF你父H研u乳酪q菌
So powerful it could decompose
rocks, trees and mountains.
但此菌力量大，能蚍纸庋沂，淠竞蜕矫}。
He devised a plan to dissolve
the entire United States.
他制定了一能蚍纸獯д美的。
At first your father gave this
swine information because...
起初你父Ho了@下流坯子的Y是因...
Please, Mr Reardon. Allow
me to tell the story.
里D先生允S我斫榻B@。
- Your father went along...
- Mr Reardon.
你父H走了...
里D先生
It is customary in these situations for
the developer of the plan to describe it.
在@N情r下，制定者通常τM行解，
I beg your pardon. It's customary for the
private eye to tell how he figured it out.
你原。照T例，私人商v述案件的睚去}。
No, it is my right!
不，@是我的嗬！
We were able to dupe Dr Forrest by
posing as a humanitarian organization...
我_福里斯特博士要建一人道主xM
who planned to wipe out hunger
by aging cheese faster.
用快速成熟的乳酪硐琊I
- When he saw what they were doing...
- He assembled lists of our agents...
你父H看到他在做什N…
他列出了我代理人的名...
- And seemed about to go to the FBI...
- We had to drug him and bring him...
似乎他要去邦{查局告l他…
我不得不o他下…
Here, faking his death so
there'd be no investigation...
所以假b他的死亡，@泳]有邦{查局的{查了...
But while testing the mold
on a small island nearby...
但在附近的一小u上y乳酪q菌分解威力r...
The Immer Essen passed by. Some of
the passengers saw the island dissolve...
永h的埃森正好通^海域，乘客都看到u被分解的^程...
They were therefore
labeled "enemies".
他因此成橙恕
We had Neff cancel all
further tours, and our...
我船主确蛉∠了旅客的行程...
Friends systematically began to
eliminate everyone on that cruise ship!
我的朋友_始有M地清除那艘[上的每一人！
- Schweinehund!
- Jerk!
i拥墓
混蛋!
Now...
F在
We are ready. Our agents
have just returned...
我已浜昧恕４理人返回...
After planting cheese
bombs throughout America.
之後乳酪q菌武器⒁u粽美
With America destroyed,
we will win the next war.
美]有後，我②A得下一
And the one after that, too!
之後就跟容易了！
When these switches are thrown, your
meddling country will disintegrate...
@些_P被打_，你要保o的家就瓦解...
Like a moldy hunk of Liederkranz!
乳酪q菌的威力就像利德克m乾酪的馕兑饬仪颐土遥
Hold the mold, Kluck. Those
switches aren't going to be thrown.
收起你的q菌吧，克拉克，@些_P不被打_。
Und I think they will be.
是幔我想被打_的。
Halt ihn!
拿下他
Good... good.
好的，做的好
I'm sorry to prevent your
becoming a hero, Herr Reardon.
里D先生，很抱歉，不能你成榇笥⑿哿耍
Actually, it is too bad you
and I are on opposite sides.
事上，你和我站在α⒚嫔咸糟糕了。
I admire your tenacity. Under
different circumstances...
我佩服你的皂g。在不同的情r下...
I might have even allowed you to live,
perhaps as my, uh... valet, or butler.
我甚至可以你活下去，也S是我，呃…我的男W，或者管家.
And what would you have me
become, Herr Field Marshal?
你我成槭颤N，元先生？
- What?
- I said...
什N？
我是f...
What position could I hold
in your "New Order"?
在你的新秩序中我能任什N位置？
Juliet! What are you saying?
He's a Nazi! Don't beg a Nazi!
茱~！你在yf啥？
他是{粹，不要乞求{粹！
Would I be your... Reinemachefrau?
或S我能成槟愕...（德Z-女颍
Ja, you could, uh...
you could be that.
Γ你可能成槟印
- What is that? What is it?!
- Tell him.
f啥毛？神R呀！
告V他！
- Reinemachefrau.
- Rrrreinemachefrau.
（德Z-女颍
It means she could be
my... cleaning woman.
意思就是，她⒊榕.
Cleaning woman!
女!
All right, join your pals.
Let's go! Move it!
到你的朋友那去，快^去，R上！
Great work, Juliet. Go find
Carlos Rodriguez for me.
做的不e，茱~，去臀艺铱洛斯?_德里格斯磉@e。
All right.
好的。
Your having that gun won't
stop us, Herr Reardon.
里D先生，你e的子不足以全部⑺牢。
We are a dedicated people,
willing to sacrifice ourselves!
我都是I身的人，意奚自己！
There are only six bullets in
that gun. There are nine of us.
你e只有6w子，我@es有9人。
Thus at least three will survive
to throw those switches.
因此，至少有三人⑸存下砣ゴ蜷_@些_P。
OK. But who's going
to win the lottery...
好啊.但是lA得彩票...
And who's going to lose?
l？
Cowards! Fools!
懦夫！傻瓜！
I'll do it myself!
我H自泶蜷_！
Sorry, pal. You're through.
Σ黄穑夥。你走h了！！
Not... quite.
]有...安o。
At least... we got...
最後...我...
Terre Haute, India... na.
特雷霍特，印度...
Damn! They were just about
to get a public library.
死的！世界地D要Q了（他R上去弄一公共D^）。
Carlos, lock these creeps up.
卡洛斯，把害x都D起怼
With pleasure!
R上k！
OK, creeps. ? Vámonos! Let's go!
好吧！害x！都出去！
Schweinehunds! Pig dogs!
i狗不如的|西！
I pity the Devil the day you
boys start arriving in bunches.
我同情耗У哪且惶欤就你的孩子成群Y的硖酵你。
Se?or Reardon, when will
you be leaving Carlotta?
里D，你要啥r候x_卡洛塔？
- Next plane out, Carlos.
- Aha!
下班wC吧，卡洛斯。
哈！
That gives me four hours to
wash and press your pajamas.
o我四小r清洗你的睡衣。
No, thanks, Carlos.
xx，不用了，卡洛斯。
I don't think I'll be needing
my pajamas any more.
我想我不再需要睡衣了。
What a guy!
好一真性情！
What are you... doing?
你想做...神R？
Adjusting your willie.
只是{整一下你小uu的角度而已。（片子前後照哦！）
When you fell through the window,
it shifted out of whack.
你拇籼Mr，你小uu就被猛震了一下，[的位置不受用。
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
xx.
@泳透ξ颐妹玫目谖读耍
下面都是e格比?里D前面χ腥橥f^了的煽情屁了，我就不翻g了，⊥敢幌拢哼@扇互“啃”很久且是同一姿荩]啥^p性，不如看下我的另外一原字幕影V告。
我做的第一部影字幕：《不名的造握-英pZ-yuan18-原字幕-^命大逃亡》Incognito.1997.DVDRip.XviD-VH-PROD――“卧勃朗油的@U幼髌，其中也有一位法女神，不是K菲?索哦！”，有d趣盆友可以到雀鞔笞帜徽舅阉鳎注“yuan18”的就是我的版本。
最後，如果有翻g不χ，可以Email指正：fasf163@163.com，或者在http://subhd.com搜索片，o我留言：）
“躺  真 探 c 中 R 童 ”
yuan18--原字幕（翻g，字幕S，校Χ际俏遗叮海）
（完）